hey guys this looks like a fun one it
was sent to me by one of my patrons it's
got a circle inscribed in a rhombus that
means all four of these lines are
tangent lines they all touch the circle
in exactly one point and that's called
the tangent point and the rhombus has
diagonals 12 and 16 and it wants to know
what is the area of the circle if you
want to try it on your own pause it
right now cuz I'm going to solve it in 3
2 1 first let's get rid of these colors
and let's get rid of the question mark
and let's construct this vertical
diagonal this has a length of 12 m and
then if we construct the other diagonal
it's going to cut this 12 in half and
that's one of the properties of the
diagonals of a rhombus they cut each
other in half and there's another
property of the diagonals of a rhombus
they also meet at right angles let's
mark this intersection Point that's
going to be the center of the rhombus
and the center of the circle next let's
look at this longer diagonal it has a
length of 16 M and it'll split in half
to be 8 and 8 next let's focus on this
right triangle let's label the
hypotenuse C and we can do the
Pythagorean theorem it's going to be 62
+ 8^ 2 is equal to c^ 2 6 2 is 36 + 8 2
is 64 and then we can bring down the c^
2 36 + 64 is equal to 100 and then we
can square root both sides of the
equation to give us C is equal to 10 so
we now know this hypotenuse is equal to
10 and since it's a rhombus we know all
these sides are equal to 10 next let's
connect this radius to here and we know
this will also be at right angles the
radius going to the tangent point will
always be at right angles to that
tangent line let's break this into two
parts let's call this p piece a and that
means this other piece would be 10 minus
a and now we can do Pythagorean theorem
two more times let's focus on this
triangle first it'll give us r^ 2 + a^ 2
is equal to 6^ 2 next let's do this
other triangle and it will give us r^ 2
plus the quantity 10 - a^ 2 is equal to
8^2 and then let's clean these up a
little bit on this top one 62 is equal
to 36 and then we can bring down
everything else for this bottom one
let's look at the quantity 10 - a^ 2
means the same thing as 10 - A * 10 - A
and after we multiply this out it'll
give us 100 - 28 + a^ 2 and then we can
bring down the R 2 and this 8^ 2 is
equal to 64 next we can subtract 100
from both sides of the equation the left
hand side we'll have r^ 2 - 20 a + a 2
and then on the right hand side 64 - 100
is equal to -36 now we've cleaned up our
two equations and let's rearrange them
like this let's drag the r squ over here
and I want to subtract this row minus
this row this r 2us r 2 are going to
cancel other out -2 a minus nothing is
-2 a and then positive a^2 minus
positive a 2 are also going to cancel
each other out and then on the right
hand side we have -36 - 36 which will
give us -72 now to get the a by itself
we can divide both sides of the equation
by -20 and this will give us a is equal
to 3.6 let's bring this up here now that
we have a I don't think we need this top
equation anymore let's move this up here
and now for this bottom equation in the
place of the a let's plug in 3.6 6
Plus's simplify the 3.6 squar to give us
12.96 and then we can bring down
everything else let's subtract 12.96
from both sides of the equation and
that'll give us r^2 is equal to
23.04 this looks important let's clean
this up a little bit and let's bring
this up here ultimately we want to find
the area of the circle the area of a
circle is < R 2 we now know what R 2 is
equal to so in the place of this R 2
let's plug in
23.04 and this is the answer to our
question the area is equal to
23.04 piun M squar let's put a box
around it and the approximate area is
72.3 M squ how exciting